A Guide to the Sturtevant Letters, 1858-1884
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Sturtevant Letters, 1858-1884
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Sturtevant family (Illinois)
Ms1993-023
0.2 Cubic Feet 1 box
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is without restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Ann Maria Sturtevant and Owen Sturtevant were married and lived in Maquon, Knox County, Illinois. other family members lived in Springfield and Monticello, Illinois.
Scope and Content Information
There are 145 pages worth of letters in this collection ranging from 1858-1884. Most of the letters include information about family births and deaths, illnesses and daily happenings. The pre-Civil War era letters are mostly information on family and farm affairs. The letters that were written during the Civil War contain information on family affairs,information on the members of the Sturtevant family in the Union army, and local happenings. The post-civil war letters cover family affairs including the divorce of Ann Sturtevant's brother William.
Arrangement
The Sturtevant letters are arranged in alphabetical order according to the author of the letter.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Civil War; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Women -- History
Family Names:
Sturtevant family (Illinois)
Contents List
- Letters (Box 1)
  - Letters from Nancy A. Bailey to Ann Maria Sturtevant, July 1863-February 1865
  - Letters from A.G. Boyer to various Sturtevants, December 1858-October 1859
  - Letters from Elizabeth H. Durkee to Ann Maria Sturtevant, September 1860-June1870
    Scope and Content Information
    Letter to Sister Ann from Elizabeth Durkee dated September 23, 1864, mentions an uncle selling one negro and future plans to sell nine.
  - Letters from I.S. Durkee to Owen Sturtevant, December, 1860-November, 1864, n.d.
    Letter written December 8, 1860 mentioning finding eleven negroes and searching records for others. Also inquires whether the recipient, "Sir", thinks Montgomery and Durkee should go to Maryland for further searching.
  - Letters from Emily Montgomery to Ann Maria Sturtevant, October 1862-January 1865
  - Letters from F.M. Montgomery to Ann Maria Sturtevant, May 1864-November 1864
  - Letters from William A. Montgomery to Ann Maria Sturtevant, January 1865-January 1869
  - Letters from John and Jarnsia Smith to Ann and Owen Sturtevant, October 1861-February 1862, n.d.
  - Letter from F.M. Montgomery to "Sister," November 1862
  - From various to Ann Maria and Owen Sturtevant, 1857-1884, n.d.